<resources>
    <string name="app_name">PayDay</string>

    <string-array name="time_to_call_list">
        <item>ANYTIME</item>
        <item>MORNING</item>
        <item>AFTERNOON</item>
        <item>EVENING</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="pay_frequencies">
        <item>WEEKLY</item>
        <item>BIWEEKLY</item>
        <item>TWICEMONTHLY</item>
        <item>MONTHLY</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="bank_account_types">
        <item>CHECKING</item>
        <item>SAVING</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="income_types">
        <item>EMPLOYMENT</item>
        <item>BENEFITS</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="military_status">
        <item>ACTIVE</item>
        <item>NOT ACTIVE</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="residence_status">
        <item>OWN</item>
        <item>RENT</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="deposit_status">
        <item>DIRECT</item>
        <item>NON DIRECT</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="what_is_pd">What is a Payday Loan?</string>
    <string name="what_is_pd_text">A payday loan is a type of short-term borrowing where a lender will extend high interest credit based on a borrower’s income and credit profile. A payday loan’s principal is typically a portion of a borrower’s next paycheck. These loans charge high interest rates for short-term immediate credit. These loans are also called cash advance loans or check advance loans.\nBREAKING DOWN Payday Loan\nPayday loans charge borrowers high levels of interest. These loans may be considered predatory loans as they have a reputation for extremely high interest and hidden provisions that charge borrowers added fees.\nObtaining a Payday Loan\nPayday loan providers are typically small credit merchants with physical locations that allow onsite credit applications and approval. Some payday loan services may also be available through online lenders.\nTo complete a payday loan application a borrower must provide paystubs from their employer showing their current levels of income. Payday lenders often base their loan principal on a percentage of the borrower’s predicted short-term income. Many also use a borrower’s wages as collateral. Other factors influencing the loan terms also include a borrower’s credit score and credit history which is obtained from a hard credit pull at the time of application.\nPayday Loan Interest\nPayday lenders charge borrowers extremely high levels of interest which can range up to 500% in annual percentage yield (APR). Most states have usury laws that limit interest charges to less than approximately 35% however payday lenders fall under exemptions that allow for their high interest. Since these loans qualify for many state lending loopholes, borrowers should beware. Regulations on these loans are governed by the individual states with some states even outlawing payday loans of any kind.\nIn California for example a payday lender can charge a 14-day APR of 459% for a $100 loan. Finance charges on these loans are also a significant factor for borrowers as the fees can range up to approximately $18 per $100 of loan.\nAlthough the federal Truth in Lending Act does require payday lenders to disclose their finance charges, many borrowers overlook the costs. Most loans are for 30 days or less and help borrowers to meet short-term liabilities. Loan amounts on these loans are usually from $100 to $1,500. Oftentimes these loans can be rolled over for additional finance charges and many borrowers are often repeat customers. A number of court cases have been filed against these lenders as lending laws following the 2008 financial crisis have been enacted to create a more transparent and fair lending market for consumers.</string>

    <string name="put_fast">Payday Loans Put Fast Funds Into Your Hands</string>
    <string name="put_fast_text">It’s easy to occasionally find yourself in a situation where you suddenly need to pay an important expense but don’t have the necessary funds on hand. You may have to take care of emergency medical costs, a major household bill, or perhaps an outstanding debt. When such a situation arises, it’s critical to swiftly get ahold of the required funds, and that’s where payday loans come in. They represent a rapid way to obtain needed funds, and here at PaydayLoans.com, we can help connect you to one of these beneficial loans quickly and efficiently.\nWhen you go through our website to acquire a loan, every part of the process is fast. First of all, it takes just five minutes for you to complete and submit our brief loan request form. Then, we attempt to quickly connect you with a member of our vast lender network who has a loan offer for you. And best of all, if you formally accept an offer, you can receive your funds in as little as just one business day.\nNot only is acquiring a payday loan via our service an extremely quick process, but it is a simple one as well. In addition to our loan request form being brief, borrower eligibility requirements are few, and you can get help even if your credit’s not the best. The process is extremely convenient, too, as you can request funds, accept an offer, and receive your funds all from the comfort of your home or office, or really anywhere as long as you’ve got an Internet-enabled device.</string>

    <string name="how_they_work">Payday Loans: How they Work?</string>
    <string name="how_they_work_text">Know the facts before borrowing\nPayday loans are short-term loans that often are used to get through a rough spot. However, there are very few situations in which these loans actually end up being helpful. Before you use one, make sure you understand the costs and risks.\nHow do they work?\nMost often, payday loans are for no more than a few hundred bucks and need to be paid back within a couple of weeks. To get a payday loan, you typically write a check for the amount you are borrowing, plus a fee. You might leave the check with the lender, and they cash it once you are ready to repay.\nIf you can’t repay your payday loan when it comes due, you sometimes can roll it over so that the loan is extended. You don’t have to repay it, but fees keep accumulating. Some states regulate rollovers by outlawing them or limiting the number of times you can renew. Before taking out a payday loan, it\'s important to review the laws in the state where you live.\nPayday loans are sometimes marketed as no credit check loans. You don\'t need good credit scores or even a credit history, and getting approved is easy relative to more traditional loans. As a result, they are popular with people facing financial difficulties.\nKnow the costs\nIn general, payday loans are significantly more expensive than traditional loans. You may end up paying an annual percentage rate (APR) that exceeds 100 percent several times over. For example, you might pay a $20 fee to borrow $100 for two weeks. Depending on all of the terms, that calculates to an APR of more than 500 percent.\nPitfalls\nThe main pitfall with payday loans is their cost. Due to extremely high fees, they don’t help you solve the real problem. If you’re having persistent financial difficulties, payday loans only make things worse. You’re paying an extraordinarily high rate of interest which means that your expenses are just going up. As a short-term strategy—maybe once or twice in your life, if that—payday loans might get you through a rough patch. For example, you might need an emergency repair for your car so you can get to work and keep earning income.\nAs a long-term strategy, payday loans will pull you under.\nYou also can get yourself in trouble if things get out of hand. Bouncing checks that you write to the payday loan establishment can end up on your ChexSystems file and result in overdraft charges from your bank. Banks and retailers may then be unwilling to work with you. Lenders also may sue you or send your account to collections, which will ding up your credit. If you keep stretching out payday loans, you\'ll pay far more in interest and fees than you ever borrowed in the first place.\nWhat about payday loans from a bank?\nBanks have moved into the payday loan industry, most likely in order to earn more revenue. While traditional bank loans that require you to qualify based on your credit, income, and assets can be a better alternative, bank payday loans are no better than any other payday loan. They may go by a variety of names, but they\’re still expensive and risky.\nIn fact, payday loans from banks can be even worse than the loans you get at a payday loan store because the bank has access to your checking account, and you have to agree to let them pull funds from your account to repay the loan. When you borrow elsewhere, you might have more control over how and when your money leaves.</string>

    <string name="unsecured">Unsecured Personal Loan Options</string>
    <string name="unsecured_text">How They Work and the Various Types\nUnsecured loans allow you to borrow money for almost any purpose. You can use the funds to start a business, consolidate debt, or buy an expensive toy. Before you borrow, make sure you understand how these loans work and the other alternatives you may have available.\nBasics of Unsecured Personal Loans\nA lender that offers you an unsecured loan won\'t require any property or collateral to secure or guarantee the loan. With a secured loan, such as a mortgage loan, the loan is secured by property. If you don’t repay the loan, your lender has the right to sell your home and collect what you owe out of the sales proceeds. With unsecured loans, nothing specific has been pledged as collateral. This makes them a little less risky for you, the borrower, because the consequences are not as immediate if you fail to repay.\nLenders, on the other hand, take more risk with unsecured personal loans. They don’t have any property to sell if you don\'t pay the loan, but they have other options available if they want to pursue repayment—such as, for example, taking legal action against you and attempting to garnish your wages. Because lenders take more risk on unsecured loans, they generally charge higher interest rates than they for secured loans.\nYour credit is one of the most important factors in determining whether you’ll receive an unsecured loan. If you have good credit, you’ll pay lower interest rates and have more loan options available to you. With bad credit, you won\'t have as many choices, and you may need a co-signer to get approved for a loan. Whenever applying for a loan, it\'s a good idea to learn more about how credit scores work.\nLoan Types\nLenders offer several types of unsecured personal loans, and each one comes with tradeoffs. Look for the loan that best meets your needs while minimizing your costs.\nSignature loan: This is the most basic type of unsecured loan. As the name suggests, the loan is secured by nothing but your signature, or your promise to pay. You can find these loans through banks and credit unions, and you can use the money for any purpose you desire.\nThey are generally installment loans that amortize over time, so you borrow one sum of money and pay it back with a fixed monthly payment until you\'ve paid off the loan. These loans make a good choice if you’ve got good credit because they generally have relatively low interest rates. Signature loans can also help you build credit so that borrowing becomes easier and less expensive in the future. To get a signature loan, tell your bank that you’d like to borrow money using a personal loan.\nPersonal line of credit: A personal line of credit is another form of an unsecured personal loan, but instead of taking the entire loan proceeds at once, the bank will approve you for a certain amount that you can use and pay back as needed. For example, you could have a $15,000 unsecured personal line of credit and draw $5,000 of it to use for payment on an ongoing home renovation project.\nWhile you\'re paying off the $5,000 loan, you still have another $10,000 available in case an unexpected or large bill comes up, for example. As you pay down the balance, the line of credit becomes available again for you to use. You only pay interest on the portion of the credit line that you\'ve borrowed, and you may be able to get a lower rate than you would with a credit card loan.\nCredit cards as loans: Using credit cards is a form of borrowing for many people. When you use a credit card, you don’t get a lump sum at the beginning of the loan, as you do with a signature loan. Instead, each time you use your card, you effectively borrow whatever you need whenever you need it, as you would with a personal line of credit. If you need more money at a later time, you can charge more to the credit card up to your credit limit.\nCredit cards make a popular solution because once you’re approved, you can borrow money practically instantly. Unfortunately, you\'ll generally pay a quite high interest rate on credit cards. Sometimes you can get a teaser rate and borrow at zero percent for a while, but those rates eventually end. It’s easy to get in trouble with credit cards, finding yourself paying hundreds of dollars monthly in interest charges alone.\nTo use a credit card as a loan vehicle, check your mailbox, which is likely full of offers if you have good credit. You also search for online credit cards that offer zero percent or low-percentage-rate deals.\nPeer to peer loan: This newer type of funding allows you to borrow from individuals, as opposed to borrowing from a traditional lender such as a bank. Several websites allow you to post a loan request online, and people have the opportunity to step in and fund your loan. These loans, like signature loans, generally have fixed-rate installment payments and competitive interest rates. They also allow you to borrow a decent amount. However, your credit score still remains a factor in most cases.\nTo get a peer-to-peer loan, try visiting one of the popular P2P lending sites, such as Prosper.com or Lending Club.\nStudent loans: These unsecured loans offer education funding to students. They\’re often a good choice because student loans have features that you can\’t find elsewhere, such as flexible repayment options, grace periods, interest subsidies, and more. With some loans, it doesn\’t even matter if you have good credit. The only hitch with student loans is that you have to be a student.\nTo get a student loan, start by visiting the financial aid office at your school. The folks in that office, who work with these loans every day, will guide you through the process of completing the paperwork involved and help you understand your options.\nWhich Loan Makes Sense For You?\nWhen reviewing your loan options, decide which criteria are relevant to your decision and consider the following:\nStudent loans have reasonable interest rates and most individuals can likely qualify as long as they\'re enrolled in courses at an accredited college-level institution. These loans offer a longer repayment term, and also typically have a grace period before you need to start payments. However, you may only use these funds for tuition and related school costs.\nSignature and peer-to-peer loans offer funds at reasonable interest rates, and you might be able to find more attractive interest rates through a credit union or your bank, especially if you have funds on deposit. These loans often let you borrow from $1,000 up to $35,000 with a three-year repayment term. You may have trouble getting approved if your credit score falls into the "fair" category or below.\nCredit cards and personal lines of credit can provide funds for many borrowers, although the lower your credit score, the higher interest rate you\'ll be charged to compensate for the repayment risk you represent to lenders. People with good to great credit can take advantage of credit card issuers\' zero percent offers, although these usually expire after 12 to 18 months.\nSince you only borrow and pay interest on the actual amount of money you use, these loans may be more attractive and cost-effective for your personal situation. You may not be able to qualify for a larger loan if you don\'t have enough monthly income to support the lender\'s requirements.\nOptions If You Have Bad Credit\nGetting an unsecured loan when you have bad credit may be challenging, but it\'s not impossible. You\'ll have fewer choices and will likely pay higher interest rates than a borrower with good credit. If you’re having a hard time borrowing, learn about getting an unsecured loan with bad credit. If it\'s feasible, hold off on borrowing until you\'ve built your credit up to the point where you can get loans on more attractive terms.\nYou can strengthen your credit by borrowing and repaying loans, and even small loans can make a difference. If you currently have a low credit score, be proactive about rebuilding it. Try a small loan secured by cash in the bank to get some momentum.</string>

    <string name="different">Different needs, different loans</string>
    <string name="different_text">Loan proceeds can be used for a variety of purposes, from funding a new business to buying your fiancée an engagement ring. But with all of the different types of loans out there, which is best? In this article, we\'ll chart some of the more popular loans, as well as their characteristics and their usefulness in meeting consumers\' financial needs.\n1. Personal Loans\nThese loans are offered by most banks, and the proceeds may be used for virtually any expense (from buying a new stereo system to paying bills). Typically, personal loans are unsecured, and range anywhere from a few hundred to a few thousand dollars. As a general rule, lenders will typically require some form of income verification, and/or proof of other assets worth at least as much as the individual is borrowing. The application for this type of loan is typically only one or two pages in length. Approvals (or denials) are generally granted within a few days.\nThe downside is that the interest rates on these loans can be quite high: around 10% currently, for a standard 24-month loan, according to the Federal Reserve. The other negative is that these loans sometimes must be repaid within two years, making it impractical for individuals looking to finance very large or long-term projects.\nIn short, personal loans (in spite of their high interest rates) are probably the best way to go for individuals looking to borrow relatively small amounts of money, and who are able to repay the loan within a couple of years.\nNote: Bank loans are different from bank guarantees. Guarantees do not involve a direct cash transfer from bank to borrower. Instead, banks issue guarantees as a surety to a third party on behalf of one of the bank\'s customers. If the bank\'s customer fails to fulfill some contractual obligation with the third party, that party can call the bank guarantee and receive payment. These typically occur in small-business situations – a contractor negotiating with a new corporate client, say. The corporation might only accept the contractor\'s bid on the condition that he receives a guarantee from his bank, stating that in the event of default on the contract by the contractor, the bank will agree to pay a sum of money to the corporation.\n2. Credit Cards\nWhen consumers use credit cards, they are essentially taking out a loan, drawing on a line of credit on the card. Credit cards are a particularly attractive source of funds for individuals (and companies) because they are accepted by many – if not most – merchants as a form of payment.\nIn addition, to obtain a card (and, by extension, $5,000 or $10,000 worth of credit), all that\'s required is a one-page application. The credit review process is also rather quick. Written applications are typically approved (or denied) within a week or two. Online / telephone applications are often reviewed within minutes. (To find out more about this process, see "The Importance of Your Credit Rating" and "How Credit Cards Affect Your Credit Rating.") Also, in terms of their use, credit cards are extremely flexible. The money can be used for virtually anything these days, from paying college tuition to buying a drink at the local watering hole.\nThere are definitely pitfalls, however. The interest rates that most credit-card companies charge can be as high as 25% per year. In addition, a consumer is more likely to rack up debt using a credit card (as opposed to other loans) because they are so widely accepted as currency and because it\'s psychologically easier to "charge it" rather  than to fork over the same amount of cash. (To read more on this type of loan, see "Take Control of Your Credit Cards," "Credit, Debit and Charge: Sizing up the Cards in Your Wallet," and "Understanding Credit Card Interest.")\n3. Home-Equity Loans\nHomeowners may borrow against the equity they\'ve built up in their residence using a home-equity loan. In other words, the homeowner is borrowing against the value of his or her home. A good method of determining the amount of home equity available for a loan would be to take the difference between the home\'s market value and the amount still owing on the mortgage.\nThe loan proceeds may be used for any number of reasons, but are typically used to build additions or for debt consolidation. The interest rates on home-equity loans are very reasonable as well. In addition, the terms of these loans typically range from 15 to 20 years, making them particularly attractive for those looking to borrow large amounts of money. But perhaps the most attractive feature of the home-equity loan is that the interest is usually tax deductible.\nThe downside to these loans is that consumers can easily get in over their heads by mortgaging their homes to the hilt. Furthermore, home-equity loans are particularly dangerous in situations where only one family member is the breadwinner, and the family\'s ability to keep up payments might be hindered by that person\'s death or disability.\nNote: In situations like these, life/disability insurance is frequently used to help protect against the possibility of default. (To keep reading on this subject, see "Home-Equity Loans: The Costs" and "The Home-Equity Loan: What It Is And How It Works.")\n4. Home-Equity Line of Credit\nThis line of credit acts as a loan and is similar to home-equity loans in that the consumer is borrowing against his or her home\'s equity. However, unlike traditional home-equity loans, these lines of credit are revolving, meaning that the consumer may borrow a lump sum, repay a portion of the loan, and then borrow again. It\'s kind of like a credit card that has a credit limit based on your home\'s equity. These loans may be tax deductible and are typically repayable over a period of 10 to 20 years, making them attractive for larger projects.\nBecause specific amounts may be borrowed at different points in time, the interest rate charged is typically pegged to some underlying index such as the prime rate, This is both good and bad in the sense that at some times, the interest rates being charged may be quite low. However, during period of rising rates, the interest charges on outstanding balances goes up too.\nThere are other downsides as well. Because the amount that can be borrowed can be quite large (typically up to $500,000 depending upon a home\'s equity), consumers tend to get in over their heads. These consumers are often lured in by low interest rates, but when rates begin to rise, those interest charges begin racking up and the attractiveness of these loans starts to wane.\n5. Cash Advances\nCash advances are typically offered by credit-card companies as short-term loans. Other entities, such as tax-preparation organizations, may offer advances against an expected IRS tax refund or against future income earned by the consumer.\nWhile cash advances may be easy to obtain, there are many downsides to this type of loan. For example:\nThey are not typically tax deductible.\nLoan amounts are typically in the hundreds of dollars, making them impractical for many purchases, particularly large ones.\nThe effective interest rate charges and related fees can be very high.\nIn short, cash advances are a fast alternative for obtaining money (funds are typically available on the spot), but because of the numerous pitfalls, they should be considered only as a last resort. (Learn more about cash advances in "Payday Loans Don't Pay.")\n6. Small Business Loans\nThe Small Business Administration (SBA) or your local bank typically extends small business loans to would-be entrepreneurs, but only after they\'ve submitted (and received approval for) a formal business plan. The SBA and other financial institutions typically require that the individual personally guarantee the loan, which means that they will probably have to put up personal assets as collateral in case the business fails. Loan amounts can range from a few thousand to a few million dollars, depending on the venture.\nWhile the term of the loan may vary from institution to institution, typically, consumers will have between five and 25 years to repay the loans. The amount of interest incurred from the loan depends on the lending institution in which the loan is made. Keep in mind that borrowers can negotiate with the lending institution with regard to the level of interest charged. However, there are some loans on the market that offer a variable rate.\nSmall business loans are the way to go for anyone looking to fund a new or existing business. However, be forewarned: Getting a business plan approved by the lending institution may be difficult. In addition, many banks are unwilling to finance cash businesses because their books (i.e. tax records) often do not accurately reflect the health of the underlying business.</string>

    <string name="good_idea">When Are Personal Loans a Good Idea?</string>
    <string name="good_idea_text">There are some circumstances in which a personal loan might be a smart move.\nPersonal loans can be a viable option in a variety of circumstances. First, let’s define a personal loan. Some loans are earmarked for a specific purchase. You buy a home with a mortgage loan, you purchase a car with an auto loan and you pay for college with a student loan.\nBut a personal loan can be used for just about anything. Some lenders want to know what you will do with the money they lend you, but as long as you’ve borrowed it for a responsible and legal reason, you can do what you want with it.\nBut what does that mean for you? With a mortgage, your home is the collateral. Similarly, with an auto loan, the car you buy is the collateral. Because a personal loan often has no collateral—it is “unsecured”—the interest rate will probably be higher. There are also secured personal loans, if you want to lower your costs.\nHere are five circumstances in which a personal loan might be a good idea.\n1. Consolidate Credit Cards\nIf you have one or more credit cards that are charged to the max, you could get a personal loan to consolidate all the charges into one monthly payment. What makes this scenario even more appealing: The interest rate on the loan could be considerably lower than the annual percentage rates (APRs) on your credit cards.\n2. Refinance Student Loans\nRefinancing student loans can provide some financial relief. Your student loan interest rate may be 6.8% or higher, depending on the type of loan you have. But you might be able to get a personal loan with a lower interest rate that allows you to pay off your loan(s) faster.\nHere are the issues: Student loans come with tax advantages. Also, if lawmakers were to offer any loan forgiveness programs in the future, in addition to those in place now, your refinanced student loans would not be eligible.\nIf you use a personal loan to pay off all or a portion of a student loan, you will lose the ability to deduct your interest payments (when you file your income taxes) along with the benefits that come with some loans, such as forbearance and deferment. And if your balance is sizable, a personal loan probably won’t cover it anyway. Think through all the issues very carefully before choosing to refinance your student loans.\n3. Finance a Purchase\nFinancing a purchase depends on whether it is a want or a need. If you’re going to take out a loan anyway, getting a personal loan and paying the seller in cash might be a better deal than financing through the seller. Don’t ever make a decision about financing on the spot, though. Ask the seller for an offer and compare it to what you could get through a personal loan. Then you can decide which is the right choice.\n4. Pay for a Wedding\nAny large event—such as a wedding—qualifies, if you would end up putting all associated charges on your credit card without being able to pay them off within a month. A personal loan for a large expense like this might save you a considerable amount on interest charges, provided it has a lower rate than your credit card.\n5. Improve Your Credit\nA personal loan might help your credit score in three ways. First, if your credit report shows mostly credit card debt, a personal loan might help your “account mix.” Having different types of loans is often favorable to your score.\nSecond, it may lower your credit utilization ratio—the amount of total credit you’re using compared to your credit limit. The lower the amount of your total credit you use, the better your score. Having a personal loan increases the total amount you have available to use.\nAnd paying back the loan on time is, of course, always good for your credit score.\nThe Bottom Line\nPersonal loans can be useful, given the right circumstances. For example, most people can’t afford to pay cash for a home, making a mortgage loan a necessity. Be sure to consult with a trustworthy financial institution and weigh your options.</string>

    <string name="privacy_policy">Read our <u>privacy policies</u> before you start to fill the data</string>

    <string name="how_it_works_title">How it works</string>
    <string name="how_it_works">We have developed an easy-to-understand online process where everything runs like clockwork. Take three simple steps and find the money you need in your pocket.</string>
    <string name="step1">Fill Out a Short Form\nIt takes up to 5 minutes to fill out our online form with some basic information. We’re concerned about your safety and keep your personal details secured.\nNo Hidden Fees</string>
    <string name="step2">Get Connected with a Lender\nAfter you submit, we’ll connect you with a suitable lender and you’ll receive an answer. If a lender decides to work with you, we’ll redirect you to their website where you can finalize your loan.\nFast Access to Lenders</string>
    <string name="step3">Receive Your Money\nAfter you’re approved, e-sign the necessary documents and have your cash directly deposited to your bank account as soon as the next business day.\nQuick Results\n</string>

</resources>
